# Pengyu Cheng

### **Research Interests**

My research interests focus on Bayesian deep learning and its applications in natural language processing. Currently, I am doing research on matching and optimizing problems of discrete distributions via probabilities measurement methods, *e.g.* discrete Wasserstein distance and Wasserstein gradient flow.

# **Education**

Duke University 08/2017–Present

Ph.D. Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Tsinghua University 08/2013–07/2017

B.S., Mathematics and Statistics

## **Publications**

o **P. Cheng**, C. Liu, C. Li, D. Shen, H. Ricardo, and L. Carin. "Straight-Through Estimator as Projected Wasserstein Gradient Flow", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Workshop, 2018 **Spotlight** 

o C. Liu, J. Zhuo, **P. Cheng**, R. Zhang, J. Zhu, and L. Carin. "Accelerated First-order Methods on the Wasserstein Space for Bayesian Inference", arXiv preprint arXiv:1807.01750, 2018

# Experience

#### Information Initiative at Duke (iiD)

08/2017-Present

Research Assistant Adviser: Lawrence Carin

Distribution matching and optimization problems and their applications in natural language processing.

#### Tsinghua Intelligent Vision Group (IVG)

03/2016-07/2016

Student Researcher Adviser: Jiwen Lu

Deep metric learning for person re-identification based on sequential frames information.

#### Student Research Program at Tsinghua

11/2015-05/2017

Student Researcher Adviser: Xuegong Zhang

Non-parametric k-sample tests using statistics which are based on local maximum energy distance.

#### Beijing Sogou Information Service Co., Ltd.

08/2014-09/2014

Research Internship Mentor: Mao Wang

Polygonal line-like city road data smoothing via Spline Interpolation; road data compressing via Douglas-Peucker algorithm.

#### **Awards**

o Fellowship of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Duke	08/2017
o First in Duke-Tsinghua Machine Learning Summer School (1/112)	08/2017
o Academic Excellence Award of Tsinghua University (top 30%)	10/2014
o Top 5 in the 18-th "Sogou Cup" Artificial Intelligence Programming Contest (5/200)	04/2014
o Silver mdeal in the 28-th Chinese Mathematical Olympiad (CMO)	01/2013

# **Technical Strengths**

**Computer Languages**: Python (Tensorflow, Pytorch), R, C/C++

Software & Tools: LaTeX, Emacs, Mathematica, MATLAB, Excel, Markdown